Now we have a board, copy a similar board and sew it together.
In order to see the wrinkle effect more clearly, I lengthen the board below.
When the two long lines are sewed together, there is no wrinkle when it naturally falls.
Unless there is an external force dragging or supporting a certain point.
But when the length of the two lines is the same,
because the long side board is more, it will pile up.
The position along the sewing line is the most obvious.
The center point of the double-sided selection can be activated.
After that, it can be retracted or rotated with the center as the basis.
After retracting, the length of the sewing line is different.
After opening the simulation,
because the board above is frozen,
so it will not be deformed,
and the longer board will form a wrinkle because of the function of the sewing line.
The characteristic of this wrinkle is that there are a lot of wrinkles in the sewing line.
This rectangular board is also often used to show the edge of the clothing.
The particle strength will also affect the texture and effect of the wrinkle.
The board is made up of a triangular grid.
The particle strength is the distance between the top of the grid,
so the smaller the particle strength, the more the grid surface.
So after reducing the particle strength,
the number of faces increases,
just like the increase in the number of lines of the curve,
it will become smoother.
The detail wrinkle appears.
This is the result.
Thank you for watching.
You have made a good change to the basic of the fabric.
In addition to the particle strength,
the simulation effect will be affected,
and the type of grid will also be affected.
In the menu in the right-hand corner,
you can select to convert the grid to a rectangular grid.
The fabric of the rectangular grid will be more flexible than the triangular grid,
and there are fewer uneven parts.
The rectangular grid is prioritized in the outer or inner line of the board.
This is the result.
Thank you for watching.
It is possible to arrange the grid from the outside line or the inside line, and then move to the middle position, and the layout may be more messy, so the fold of the panel is still not smooth.
In addition to the fact that the panel can be divided into four parts, it can also be remeshed.
After the panel is remeshed, the layout of the grid is organized according to the layout of the 2D window.
You can see that the layout of the grid is very, very neat.
After each change of the particle diameter, the reset grid will re-arrange once.
Therefore, you can see that if the panel is rotated or the shape itself is special, then the grid arrangement will be crooked.
This simulation will not work well.
If you just rotate and do not change the particle diameter, there will be no problem.
For rectangular panels, just rotate them to the level or value position.
Then change the particle diameter, and you will return to the original state.
After the simulation, you can see that although the particle diameter is 20, but because the grid arrangement is very neat, the fold area looks very smooth.
You can see that the number of folds in the overall shape is no different.
The shape is also similar to the previous one.
However, the version of the reset grid is different from the default grid type, and its calculation will be larger.
So when the particle diameter is relatively small, such as 5 or below, there will be some lags.
The triangle shape also has its own length, which is stable.
Sometimes we don't need to reduce the particle diameter for the entire panel, as long as the details are shown.
Select the grid brush tool, you can select some of the panels on the panel and divide the grid.
After dividing, the particle diameter of the grid becomes smaller, and the grid surface number increases.
You can see that some inconspicuous cracks have appeared before.
Once the division command is applied, if the overall particle diameter is reduced, the area of the division will be reduced equally.
Generally speaking, when a part is divided, it will display in a special color.
If you can't see it from a certain perspective, you can zoom in or out to see it.
Select the right button to delete the division, and return to the normal grid layout.
For this kind of long and short gap, we can directly increase the width and length of the panel to increase the gap.
The same can be done for the vertical grid.
As you can see, the middle line of the grid is the horizontal line of the grid, and the horizontal line is the vertical line of the grid.
The vertical line of the grid is the horizontal line of the grid.
We can also make the grid larger.